<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>David's Town</title>
  <subtitle>David Piper's Website</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>David Piper</name>
    <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://davids.town/" rel="self" />
  <id>urn:uuid:6018DCD4-2BBD-45D6-8745-c0deba55c1ef</id>
  <updated>2026-01-01T06:51:41Z</updated>

  <entry>
    <title>Origin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/origin"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:91E46AE3-31A8-45D7-A7C6-A7B63DED99D4</id>
    <updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Origin</h1><p>Welcome to my blog! This site is built with my own custom site generator, so I thought I'd use this first post to describe how it works.</p><p>There are three GitHub repos for this blog. It could potentially be condensed into a single repo but it felt cleaner to split it up into its logical parts.</p><ol><li>The Github Pages repository</li><li>The Blog Reel</li><li>The Site Generator</li></ol><h3>The Github Pages repository</h3><p>This is what you're seeing - it's the repo that contains the website tree. Github Pages now supports HTTPS with custom domains too! 🎉</p><h3>The Blog Reel</h3><p>This is a flat repo of markdown files with the individual posts. They're named in a way that forces both alphabetical and chronological order - for example, this file is named <code>00001-origin.md</code>. There's also a folder called <code>assets</code>, which willhold what it says one day soon.</p><p>The markdown files actaully start with a bit of HTTP-esque metadata for things like url, title, tags, publish date, etc. Most of this is really only needed to keep the Atom feed happy.</p><p>Then there's an empty line, and then the markdown starts.</p><h3>The Site Generator</h3><p>The site generator repo contains scripts to build the site from the blog reel. It pulls the blog reel down, feeds it through about 300 lines of Python and generates the full HTML tree for the blog.</p><p>The markdown to HTML conversion happens in a single line. The rest of the Python code is a combination of extracting data from the raw posts and using a poor-man's HTML templating system ~definitely not just find-and-replacing pre-defined symbols~ to generate the home page, the Atom feed, and all the blog post pages, with sequential links.</p><p>The full HTML tree is then copied into the Github Pages repo, committed and pushed.</p><p>And that's it!</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The English alphabet is a singly-linked list</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/alphabet"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:C0334BF2-8512-45F9-BFC5-602F9F258BB1</id>
    <updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>The English alphabet is a singly-linked list</h1><p>It occurred to me the other day that one of the most common uses of a singly-linked list is the English alphabet.</p><p>At least, I've never memorised it backwards. Even if I did, I suppose I'd only have two singly-linked lists without more practice anyway.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>"Force field"</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/force-field"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:E624476B-6726-4B91-B8C0-1E602DEF3183</id>
    <updated>2020-07-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>"Force field"</h1><p>In science fiction, the term "force field" is wonderfully self-descriptive.</p><p>It's a field of force that fields force.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Magic Carpet Rag</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/magic-carpet-rag"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:079C718D-8ECF-476E-AEDE-3279BAD77022</id>
    <updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Magic Carpet Rag</h1><p>A few weeks ago I finished writing my second piano ragtime!</p><p>It's called <a href="https://musescore.com/davidpiper/magic-carpet-rag">Magic Carpet Rag</a>.</p><p>Check it out, if you're into that sort of thing. Hope you enjoy it!</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reading the writing on the wall</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/reading-the-writing-on-the-wall"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:56EDC3E6-0A68-432C-80EC-B49781200EE0</id>
    <updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Reading the writing on the wall</h1><p>I've been playing a lot of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(game)">Go</a> recently, and catching up on the progress of Go AIs since <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlphaGo_versus_Lee_Sedol">AlphaGo beat Lee Sedol 4-1</a> in March 2016. That "1" was probably the last game a human will ever win against top Go AIs.</p><p>In the last few years, humans have been learning from robots. New shapes and strategies have been discovered and some very old strategies have made a comeback. Some Go AIs are able to provide move-by-move "win percentages" which are enormously helpful for evaluating moves in game reviews. There are caveats though - there is a duality to learning and teaching, and AIs are taught how to play Go, not how to teach it.</p><p>Normally (in the sense of "norms" vs. "rules") it is polite to resign a game when it has become clear you cannot win.</p><p>But the thing is: how do you <em>know</em>?</p><p>A stronger player will generally know before a weaker player, and a robot will likely "know" well before most humans. Even players of the same strength may have different opinions depending on their skill in different aspects of the game. Which means in many games there is a time when one player knows the game is over, but the other player hasn't realised yet and continues playing.</p><p>This reminded me of a quote from Iain M. Banks' <em>The Player of Games</em>. At this point in the story, Gurgeh - the main character - is many days into an immensely large and difficult game of strategy with the (other) greatest game player in the galaxy, Emperor Nicosar. After weeks of play:</p><blockquote>  <p><em>It goes on until it ends</em>, Gurgeh thought to himself one day, and at the same time as the banality of the thought struck him, he saw that it was over. The climax had been reached. It was done, destroyed, could be no more. It was not finished, but it was over. A terrible sadness swamped him, took hold of him like a piece and made him sway and nearly fall, so that he had to walk to his seat and pull himself on to it like an old man.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>'Oh...' he heard himself say.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>He looked at Nicosar, but the emperor hadn't seen it yet.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>...</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>Gurgeh couldn't believe it. The game was over; couldn't <em>anybody</em> see that? He looked despairingly around the faces of the officials, the spectators, the observers and Adjudicators. What was wrong with them all? He looked back at the board, hoping desperately that he might have missed something, made some mistake that meant there was still something Nicosar could do, that the perfect dance might last a little longer. He could see nothing. It was done.</p></blockquote><p>The writing is on the wall whether you can read it or not.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So open-minded that our brains fall out</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/brains-fall-out"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:A64B2217-1CAD-44A4-87EB-01F45A85210F</id>
    <updated>2020-11-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>So open-minded that our brains fall out</h1><p>I've been thinking about this a lot lately, and finally tracked down the original source:</p><blockquote>  <p>Let us keep our minds open, by all means, as long as that means keeping our sense of perspective and seeking an understanding of the forces which mould the world. <em>But don’t keep your minds so open that your brains fall out!</em> There are still things in this world which are true and things which are false; acts which are right and acts which are wrong, even if there are statesmen who hide their designs under the cloak of high-sounding phrases.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>— Walter Kotschnig, November 8, 1939</p></blockquote><p>Coincidentally, I'm part way through <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34890015-factfulness"><em>Factfulness</em>, by Hans Rosling</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In His Image</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/in-his-image"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:364290DD-6DC1-47FE-840B-9D2595F539AF</id>
    <updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>In His Image</h1><p>I finished <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Talos_Principle">The Talos Principle</a> the other day. I offer no spoilers. The whole game was an incredible experience and I highly recommend it if you enjoy puzzle games and philosophy.</p><p>Since the opening few levels, I've been dancing with the difficult questions it asks about humanity. Many of these questions weave beautifully with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuval_Noah_Harari">Yuval Noah Harari</a>'s philosophy of stories: how stories are a defining characteristic of our species, and how the stories we tell shape our view of reality.</p><p>I don't know the Bible very well, but I know some of the more popular lines and verses. One of them (which I've since learned comes from Genesis 1:27) is:</p><blockquote>  <p>God created man in His own image.</p></blockquote><p>Combined with my thougths about The Talos Principle, I suddenly realised that this line contains an enormous, almost meta, irony.</p><p>For what is the Bible, but man creating God in <em>his</em> own image?</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Could the sun be invisible?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/invisible-sun-nerd-snipe"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:7A890B89-1E84-414C-9F27-8F5AE53470DE</id>
    <updated>2021-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Could the sun be invisible?</h1><p>I went down a rabbit hole recently, pondering the question:</p><blockquote>  <p>Assuming a species has evolved eyes, could they evolve in such a way that the sun is invisible?</p></blockquote><p>There are a few more assumptions needed here, like the sun being the primary source of heat/energy for the celestial body that the species is evolving on, etc. Let's just say it's a species evolving on Earth.</p><p>Below is a graph<a href="https://www.fondriest.com/environmental-measurements/parameters/weather/solar-radiation/">[1]</a> of our sun's radiation spectrum:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/solar-radiation.jpg" title="Graph of the solar radiation spectrum, with a peak around the 500nm wavelength"></img></p><p>We can see that the visible part of the spectrum aligns with the peak area of the specturm. In fact the source<a href="https://www.fondriest.com/environmental-measurements/parameters/weather/solar-radiation/">[1]</a> actually has a short snippet about this:</p><blockquote>  <p>Predators would not be able to efficiently hunt prey without light from the sun and prey would not be able to take advantage of dark areas if predators were adapted to dark habitats. Human eyes are adapted to the visible spectrum, though some other species can see ultraviolet light in addition to colors.</p></blockquote><h2>Tangent: Why isn't the sky purple?</h2><p>Contrary to popular belief, the sky is not blue because of the ozone in the stratosphere. The sky appears blue due to the scattering of all wavelengths of light by all gases in the atmosphere. This is known as diffuse sky radiation. I'll let let <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diffuse_sky_radiation">Wikipedia explain</a>:</p><blockquote>  <p>The dominant radiative scattering processes in the atmosphere are Rayleigh scattering and Mie scattering; they are elastic, meaning that a photon of light can be deviated from its path without being absorbed and without changing wavelength.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>Earth's atmosphere scatters short-wavelength light more efficiently than that of longer wavelengths. Because its wavelengths are shorter, blue light is more strongly scattered than the longer-wavelength lights, red or green. Hence, the result that when looking at the sky away from the direct incident sunlight, the human eye perceives the sky to be blue.</p></blockquote><p>So if short-wavelength light is scattered more efficiently, and the shortest wavelength the human eye can perceive is violet, not blue, why isn't the sky violet? (Naturally, there's an <a href="https://xkcd.com/1145">xkcd for this</a>.)</p><p>It turns out the sky isn't violet because of the way our eyes have evolved<a href="https://math.ucr.edu/home/baez/physics/General/BlueSky/blue_sky.html">[2]</a>:</p><blockquote>  <p>We have three types of colour receptors, or cones, in our retina.  They are called red, blue and green because they respond most strongly to light at those wavelengths.  As they are stimulated in different proportions, our visual system constructs the colours we see.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>When we look up at the sky, the red cones respond to the small amount of scattered red light, but also less strongly to orange and yellow wavelengths. The green cones respond to yellow and the more strongly scattered green and green-blue wavelengths. The blue cones are stimulated by colours near blue wavelengths, which are very strongly scattered. If there were no indigo and violet in the spectrum, the sky would appear blue with a slight green tinge. But the most strongly scattered indigo and violet wavelengths stimulate the red cones slightly as well as the blue, which is why these colours appear blue with an added red tinge. The net effect is that the red and green cones are stimulated about equally by the light from the sky, while the blue is stimulated more strongly. This combination accounts for the pale sky blue colour.</p></blockquote><blockquote>  <p>It may not be a coincidence that our vision is adjusted to see the sky as a pure hue. We have evolved to fit in with our environment; and the ability to separate natural colours most clearly is probably a survival advantage.</p></blockquote><h2>Return</h2><p>Now we return to the original question: could eyes evolve in such a way that the sun is invisible?</p><p>Among species with eyes, it seems reasonable to assume that those who see more wavelengths of light probably have a survival advantage over those who see fewer. Imagine if we could only see colours at the red end of the visible spectrum - we'd be missing out on a lot of the world. But what if we were missing out on the <em>whole</em> world of colour? What if our eyes - those rods and cones - evolved differently?</p><p>And now we have to stop, because if eyes cannot see any wavelengths emitted by the sun, can we still call them eyes?</p><p>I think the answer is no. And therefore my original question is poorly formed.</p><p>We understand "eyes" and "vision" <em>specifically</em> in relation to the visible spectrum of a sun or light source. We actually have another sense that can detect the infrared radiation from the sun (touch) - it tells our body how warm it is. We don't descibe that as 'vision', and we don't think of it as 'seeing' heat.</p><p>So I've basically <a href="https://xkcd.com/356/">nerd sniped</a> myself. The sun can't be invisible for any species with sight, because our definitions of "eyes" and "sight" directly depend on that source of light.</p><p>Seems I need a more robust mental model for thinking about the senses.</p><h2>Sources</h2><p>[1] Fondriest Environmental, Inc. “Solar Radiation and Photosynethically Active Radiation.” Fundamentals of Environmental Measurements. 21 Mar. 2014. Web. &lt; <a href="https://www.fondriest.com/environmental-measurements/parameters/weather/solar-radiation/">https://www.fondriest.com/environmental-measurements/parameters/weather/solar-radiation/</a> &gt;.</p><p>[2] Philip Gibbs “Why is the sky blue?” UC Riverside. May 1997. Web. &lt; <a href="https://math.ucr.edu/home/baez/physics/General/BlueSky/blue_sky.html">https://math.ucr.edu/home/baez/physics/General/BlueSky/blue_sky.html</a> &gt;</p><p><em>(No, I don't remember how to do references properly, but I think that covers everything.)</em></p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>La Nuit de Noël</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/la-nuit-de-noel"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:4EC80362-B19C-4E2C-BE77-AEBB869E9452</id>
    <updated>2021-12-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>La Nuit de Noël</h1><p>I thought it would be fun to start composing pieces in the style of composers, artists and genres that I enjoy.</p><p>The motivation for this is both education and laziness:</p><ul><li>Education because I'll learn a lot about the music I'm imitating</li><li>Laziness because it means I don't have to expend quite as much creative energy to come up wiht something <em>wholly</em> original.</li></ul><p>It's really just another form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constrained_writing">Constrained Writing</a>. With an idea to start simple in my imitation, I picked Erik Satie's three <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-Xm7s9eGxU">Gymnopédies</a>.</p><p>The result is a piece that, to me, seems to fit a quiet, snowy night in the cramped, cobblestoned streets of somewhere like Victorian England.</p><p>I think it's <em>slightly</em> too diatonic or consonant compared to Satie's Gymnopédies, but I really liked the whimsical and satisfying conclusion. Particularly at this time of year.</p><p>So I present <a href="https://soundcloud.com/davidpiper44/la-nuit-de-noel" target="_blank">La Nuit de Noël</a>, an offering of muted festivity.</p><p>Merry Christmas 🎄</p><p>(<a href="/blog-assets/la-nuit-de-noël.pdf" target="_blank">Sheet music</a>)</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Make it so good that it ruins everything else for you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/good-ruins"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:3A1EEE28-9A22-4EB5-954E-1CF73ADEC426</id>
    <updated>2022-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Make it so good that it ruins everything else for you</h1><p>That's the post.</p><p>You can apply it to individual parts, or the whole of any creative work you produce.</p><p>It's not productive or sustainable advice for everything, but people will notice.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Maths of a Vitamin B6 Overdose</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/vitamin-b6-overdose"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:7C071141-56C0-4A4F-866C-78303E370AA4</id>
    <updated>2022-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>The Maths of a Vitamin B6 Overdose</h1><h2>Setting the scene</h2><p>This year I've spent 8 months looking for answers to some bizarre, elusive and unnerving physical symptoms.</p><p>The first diagnosis was stress and anxiety — which was quite true — but that couldn't explain (among other symptoms) why each morning I couldn't feel where my hands were. It's not just that they were numb — or on fire, depending on the morning — my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proprioception">proprioception</a> was completely busted. </p><p>After months of blood tests, therapy, heart tests, Parkinsons tests, neuro-physiotherapy, nerve conduction studies and MRIs, I was sitting in a hotel room after a work on-site when I recieved an email from my mum.</p><p>By sheer coincidence, someone in her office had sent her <a href="https://www.tga.gov.au/news/safety-updates/peripheral-neuropathy-supplementary-vitamin-b6-pyridoxine">this update from the TGA</a>, which she passed on to me because the description of the peripheral neuropathy symptoms matched many of the symptoms I'd been experiencing.</p><blockquote>  <p>Adverse event reports submitted to the TGA suggest there is a lack of awareness that vitamin B6, which is present in many multivitamin and mineral supplements, can cause peripheral neuropathy. In response, the TGA has strengthened labelling requirements so products containing daily doses over 10mg of vitamin B6 must carry a warning about peripheral neuropathy.</p></blockquote><p>After a bit of Googling I found the Wikipedia page for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Megavitamin-B6_syndrome">Megavitamin-B6 Syndrome</a>, and sat very still (difficult when your fingers twitch uncontrollably) mentally ticking off <em>every single symptom</em> listed.</p><p>But I've never taken Vitamin B6 supplements.</p><p>Or at least, I thought I hadn't.</p><p>After a quick rummage in my luggage, I discovered the Magnesium supplement I'd been taking every day since March also contained a 41.1mg dose of Pyridoxine hydrochloride (i.e. Vitamin B6). The recommended daily dietary intake of Vitamin B6 for someone my age is about 1.1mg.</p><p>I'd been poisoning myself with a supplement I didn't even know contained B6 because I didn't read the fine print.</p><p>Thanks Blackmore's.</p><p>So naturally I stopped taking the Magnesium immediately. From the Wikipedia page, the half-life of B6 in the body is 33 days. And there's this delighful footnote:</p><blockquote>  <p>In the immediate 2–6 weeks following discontinuation of vitamin B6, patients may experience a symptom progression before gradual improvement begins. This is known as coasting and is encountered in other toxic neuropathies.</p></blockquote><p>As I write this, it's Day 36, and my symptoms did indeed progress for a while, but have started to ease noticeably. They're not completely gone though, and won't be for a few more months.</p><h2>Math overdose</h2><p>Half-life is not elimination, so I thought I'd do some quick maths to figure out:</p><ul><li>How much Vitamin B6 I had in my body the day I stopped taking the Magnesium</li><li>How much Vitamin B6 I should have had in my body that day</li><li>How much Vitamin B6 I had in my body on Day 33 (one half-life later)</li></ul><h3>Assumptions:</h3><ul><li>Every day I don't take a supplement, I'm ingesting the RDI of 1.1mg Vitamin B6.</li><li>Every day I do take the supplement, I'm ingesting the RDI plus 41.1mg from the Magnesium tablet (42.2mg in total).</li><li>I had a negligible amount of Vitamin B6 in my body on March 1 (close enough).</li><li>The half-life of B6 in the body is 25-33 days. Let's assume a worst-case 33 days.</li></ul><h3>Facts:</h3><ul><li>I started the Magnesium supplements on March 2</li><li>I stopped taking them on October 10 (222 days later)</li><li>A compound's half-life is the time it takes for half the mass of the compound to be eliminated from the system</li></ul><h3>Working:</h3><p>The half-life equation is a decreasing exponentional:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/half-life-equation.jpg" width="300" title="The Half-Life Equation"></img></p><p>As each daily dose of B6 is the same (42.2mg), we can use the following summation to find out how much is in my body on the day I dicovered I had been poisoning myself. The summation is "counting backwards" from the previous day's dose:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/day-0-summation-supplemented.jpg" title="Summation for how much Vitamin B6 was in my body after supplemtnation for 222 days"></img></p><p>The result of this summation is approximately 1970mg or 1.97 grams.</p><p>The amount of B6 I <em>should</em> have had in my body is the same summation, but with a healthy daily dose of 1.1mg:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/day-0-summation-normal.jpg" title="Summation for how much Vitamin B6 should have been my body with no supplementation for 222 days"></img></p><p>The result is approximately 51mg, and is a good approximation for the healthy steady-state level, given the small numbers involved.</p><p><strong>So I was walking around with about 38x the recommended healthy amount of Vitamin B6 in my body.</strong></p><p>After 33 days of no supplementation, we can determine the amount of B6 left in my body with this summation:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/day-33-summation.jpg" width="500" title="Summation for how much Vitamin B6 was still in my body after 33 days without eupplementation, following 222 days of supplementation"></img></p><p>Which is approximately 1010mg. Just over 1g. That's still 20x what I should have floating around.</p><ul><li>After another 33 days: 531mg (10x)</li><li>After another 33 days: 292mg (5.7x)</li><li>After another 33 days: 172mg (3x)</li><li>After another 33 days: 112mg (2.2x)</li><li>After another 33 days: 82mg (1.6x)</li><li>After another 33 days: 69mg (1.4x)</li></ul><p>The exponential decline means it will be a long time before I actually get back to the 51mg mark exactly, but it's safe to assume after 6 months I'll be back under 100mg, which is well and truly safe.</p><h2>Final note</h2><p>Not all Magnesium supplements have Vitamin B6 in them, I just got unlucky. But I've sworn off all supplements for at least 6 months anyway. My occasional multivitamin was also providing a bit of a bump (~3mg), and while the Vitamin D capsules are pure, I'm putting them on hold for a bit too.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Best news ever</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/vitamin-b6-normal"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:C0E5CFA5-44A1-4875-9ED4-3AD8848861C6</id>
    <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Best news ever</h1><p>A whole year later:</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/b6-normal.png" width="700" title="Vitamin B6 levels are normal again!" style="border: 1px solid gray;"></img></p><p>Down from 784 nmol/L on January 27, 2023.</p><p>Which means the elimination half-life was about 20 days, not 33 days.</p><p>Which means on October 10, 2022 — the day I stopped taking the magnesium — my test would have been roughly 33,645 nmol/L, or ~300x the healthy limit.</p><p>It's nice to be normal again.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ranna's Lullaby</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/rannas-lullaby"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:3A6F321A-CAEB-44CE-ABC1-84477805B808</id>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Ranna's Lullaby</h1><p>I finally got back to a piece I started on April 19 last year.</p><p>"Ranna, the Sleepbringer" is a character from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Kingdom_(book_series)">Old Kingdom series</a> by <a href="https://garthnix.com/">Garth Nix</a>.</p><p>The first book, Sabriel, recently celebrated its 25th anniversary.</p><p>I liked the piece so much that I asked professional Australian pianist and Twitch streamer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@lara6683">Lara de Wit</a> to play it.</p><p>🎼 <a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/10660186">Sheet music</a> </p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u0_Bqjm_xxk" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" style="display: block;margin: 16px auto;border: black 1px solid;"></iframe>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First attempt at orchestral composing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/orchestral-scoring-1-wip"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:96338399-5983-4D48-B6DD-2E588B66FD77</id>
    <updated>2023-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>First attempt at orchestral composing</h1><p>Sam and I are composing an orchestral piece. The result so far sounds a bit like a mash of superhero movie and military observance.</p><p>A few thoughts:</p><ul><li>Phrases of 7 bars are tricky</li><li>Samples sound clunky for whole sections, and even clunkier for solos</li><li>French Horns are way quieter than I expected</li><li>You can soften or harden a soloist's instrument by doubling with other instruments doubling with other instruments</li><li>That sort of means it's not a solo anymore though</li></ul><p>🔊 <a href="/blog-assets/audio/SectionsGoodEnoughToName.m4a">Audio v0.1</a> </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Super Mario Bros. Medley</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/super-mario-bros-medley"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:E2FE3112-FC2D-49C4-B947-8B99D453E441</id>
    <updated>2023-08-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Super Mario Bros. Medley</h1><p>Years ago, I came across <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sonya_Belousova">Sonya Belousova's</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lID0A5p0_SY">incredible arrangement</a> of the Super Mario Bros. themes.</p><p>Back then, I remember thinking "I wish I could play that well". And I still can't, but I'm getting closer, so I spent some time transcribing the arrangement.</p><ul><li>Part 1: Overworld Theme (WIP)</li><li>Part 2: <a href="/blog-assets/2-Underworld.pdf">Underworld Theme</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/11713435">Musescore</a>)</li><li>Part 3: <a href="/blog-assets/3-Underwater.pdf">Underwater Theme</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/11705428">Musescore</a>)</li><li>Part 4: <a href="/blog-assets/4-Fanfare.pdf">Flagpole Fanfare</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/11705455">Musescore</a>)</li></ul><p>And by "some time" I mean "way too much time". But it's been fun. And now I get to learn them!</p><p>The Overworld Theme is the hardest, I'm about 30% done (6 Aug 2023), but I'll probably be a bit short on time in the next few months so I thought I'd upload the other three before I've finished the full set.</p><p>I'm really, really happy with how they came out.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brewster-Jones' compositions for Edith Piper</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/brewster-jones-edith-piper"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:EBEEB009-2B4E-4021-BEEB-86918FE5ED4D</id>
    <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Brewster-Jones' compositions for Edith Piper</h1><p>At school, my piano teacher gave me an old Australian piece by Hooper Brewster-Jones called 'Desolation'. I didn't really understand it at the time, but I could play it well enough to pass an exam.</p><p>Back in April this year, I went looking for some other Brewster-Jones pieces to learn, and I found a lot in the Special Collections of the Adelaide University library.</p><p>And it turns out, a "Miss Edith Piper" was a student of his! He wrote at least <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/library/special/mss/brewster_jones/series-1/">3 pieces for her</a>.</p><p>Also two notes in <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/library/special/mss/brewster_jones/series-8/">Series 8</a>.</p><p>And it looks like they <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/library/special/mss/brewster_jones/series-9/">performed together</a>: “Pastoral Concerto for 2 Pianos - Edith Piper and H. Brewster-Jones”.</p><p>I also found some newspaper appearances:</p><ul><li><a href="trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/64301495">28 July, 1923</a></li><li><a href="trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/63713293">10 April, 1925</a></li><li><a href="trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/63722745">11 April, 1925</a> (same article)</li><li><a href="trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/47027728">16 October, 1926</a></li></ul><p>After some family confirmation, not only do several people remember her well, they also remember she worked with Hooper Brewster-Jones! I wonder if my piano teacher ever knew the connection.</p><p>So naturally I requested the manuscripts from the library, and transcribed them:</p><ul><li><a href="/blog-assets/brewster-jones-prelude-edith-piper.pdf">Prelude</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/10770409">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/brewster-jones-portrait-waltz-edith-piper.pdf">Portrait Waltz</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/11779600">Musescore</a>)</li></ul><p>There are some other transcriptions I might get around to, but these are the main ones. And they really, really need a human performance to do them justice.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pikachu</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/pikachu"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:DB7A4093-F54B-4C52-944E-190BD46BA99B</id>
    <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Pikachu</h1><p><img src="/blog-assets/Pikachu-Float.gif" width="800px" title="Pikachu, floating"></img></p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Carols</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/christmas-carols"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:920C4E25-252D-4B8A-8F5D-3594463E47EF</id>
    <updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Christmas Carols</h1><p>I recently spent some time digitally copying out Christmas Carols from my grandparents' oldChristmas Carol piano books. The (mostly) 4-part harmonies are wonderful.</p><ul><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Away-in-a-Manger.pdf">Away in a Manger</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23105776">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Deck-the-Halls.pdf">Deck the Halls</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23110183">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Good-King-Wenceslas.pdf">Good King Wenceslas</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23111542">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Hark-The-Herald-Angels-Sing.pdf">Hark! The Herald Angels Sing</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23124721">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Jingle-Bells.pdf">Jingle Bells</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23123290">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-O-Christmas-Tree.pdf">O Christmas Tree</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23129047">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-O-Come-All-Ye-Faithful.pdf">O Come, All Ye Faithful</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23123590">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-Silent-Night.pdf">Silent Night</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23106082">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-The-First-Noel.pdf">The First Noël</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23109751">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-The-Twelve-Days-of-Christmas.pdf">The Twelve Days of Christmas</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23125339">Musescore</a>)</li><li><a href="/blog-assets/Golden-Book-We-Three-Kings-of-Orient-Are.pdf">We Three Kings of Orient Are</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23129275">Musescore</a>)</li></ul><p>By the way, my favourite Christmas Carol is "Silver Bells".</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob-omb Battlefield</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/bob-omb-battlefield"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:B9544137-B876-4B09-BD5E-10C13B86F3C9</id>
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Bob-omb Battlefield</h1><p>Many years ago now, I arranged a ragtime-esque version of the Super Mario 64 Main Theme, Bob-omb Battlefield.</p><p>After a long time collecting undeserved dust, I thought I'd actually release it.</p><ul><li><a href="/blog-assets/Super-Mario-64-Main-Theme-Bob-omb-Battlefield.pdf">Bob-omb Battlefield</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/23302072">Musescore</a>)</li></ul><p>At the time of writing there's something broken in MuseScore's playback. I'll fix that whenever they do.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vignette I - Autumn Walk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/vignette-i-autumn-walk"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:95040377-E50F-4838-BA3C-D2DF5E03507B</id>
    <updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Vignette I: Autumn Walk</h1><p>I think I have a new format.</p><ul><li><a href="/blog-assets/Vignette-I.pdf">Vignette I: Autumn Walk</a> (<a href="https://musescore.com/user/27393070/scores/26652916">Musescore</a>)</li></ul><p>Well, had a new format. I started this one in 2023.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dear Apple, Please Fix iOS Music</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://davids.town/dear-apple-please-fix-ios-music"/>
    <id>urn:uuid:F675375A-1998-4D90-8018-71B937B2CB5A</id>
    <updated>2026-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Dear Apple,</p><p>I don't like complaining. Let alone starting a new year with a complaint. But I've been sitting on this for a while, and New Year's Day is apparently the first block of free time I've had to write about it.</p><p>Making things is hard. Collaborative software development is hard. I get it. I've mostly ignored UX and bugs over the years because the benefit I get from running a primarily Apple ecosystem at home is so much greater than the pain of any one app. But I'm consistently frustrated now: the iOS Music app's UX is buggered.</p><p>It starts with a simple question: <strong>How do I search my music library for a purchased song?</strong></p><p>I feel like this should be easy. I kind of expect it to be easy given how much money I've paid you for music over the years. It used to be easy.</p><p>Alas.</p><h3>Step 0: Disable Apple Music</h3><p>In Settings, I have <em>disabled</em> the "Show Apple Music" toggle. I have also enabled the "Show All Purchases" toggle. These settings have been like this for years.</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-0.png" title="My Music app settings" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h3>Step 1: Open the Music app</h3><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-1.png" title="My Music app home page, so to speak" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h3>Step 2: Tap the Search bubble</h3><p>I've finally gotten used to the search bubble being in the bottom-right.</p><p>Tapping Search sure does a lot of things <em>other</em> than bring up a search box, hey.</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-2.png" title="Result of tapping the search bubble" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h3>Step 3: Huh.</h3><p>I thought I disabled Apple Music.</p><p>What am I searching here?</p><p>What is Apple Music Live?</p><p>What happens if I tap on any one of those selections?</p><p>Actually, I'm curious: let's see what happens.</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-3.png" title="Every song is greyed out" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><p>I get sent to a Store-like page containing dozens of links to songs that I can't play. Tapping any of the greyed-out links pops a modal asking me... to pay for Apple Music.</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-4.png" title="I thought I disabled Apple Music" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h2>Step 4: So where the hell is my library search?</h2><p>Oh! I have to tap the search box (again), providing an intent to <em>search Apple Music</em> first.</p><p>I <em>really</em> thought I disabled Apple Music.</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-5.png" title="Search Apple Music first" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><p>Now that I'm searching Apple Music I can see there is a tab to search my Library instead.</p><p><em>I'm sure tapping "Library" will save that selection for next time. After all, I've disabled Apple&nbsp;Music.&nbsp;👀</em></p><p>(To elaborate: it does, but not between app launches, which is a shame because I close apps regularly.)</p><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-6.png" title="Remember to select Library every bloody time" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h2>Step 5: Search for a song</h2><p><img src="/blog-assets/apple-music-7.png" title="Title" width="250px" style="border: 1px solid lightgrey;"></img></p><h2>Step 6: Cry</h2><p>This is one of the most painful iOS interaction patterns I have to deal with, multiple times a day.</p><p>Please fix iOS Music.</p><p>Seasons greetings for 2026,</p><p>David.</p><p><strong>P.S:</strong> While we're here, why are there two X buttons right next to each other that do exactly the same thing? I might be conflating Safari and Music here, but the location change of "Submit" to be part of the keyboard has tripped me up so many times. Not because its location was changed (this I'm fine with) but because the original button was replaced with a destructive operation that does <strong>exactly the opposite</strong> of what it used to do.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>David Piper</name>
      <email>dpiper.public@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
  </entry>


</feed>